<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>:Lazy Hazy Days</title>
    <description>My guide to cosy, simple living</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 20:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 20:21:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Favourite Pumpkin Recipes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are slap bang in the middle of pumpkin season and I absolutely love experimenting with various pumpkin recipes to really get me in the autumn mood.&lt;br /&gt;
Here is a list of some of my favourite pumpkin recipes for you to try on these cosy autumn days…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pumpkin-pancakes&quot;&gt;Pumpkin Pancakes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pumpkin_pancakes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These fluffy pumpkin pancakes are the ultimate autumn breakfast.  They go perfectly with crispy bacon, chopped pecans and a good drizzle of maple syrup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;300g plain flour&lt;br /&gt;
75g caster sugar&lt;br /&gt;
1 tbsp baking powder&lt;br /&gt;
½ tsp salt&lt;br /&gt;
1 tsp cinnamon&lt;br /&gt;
¼ tsp ground cloves&lt;br /&gt;
¼ tsp nutmeg &lt;br /&gt;
350ml milk&lt;br /&gt;
2 eggs&lt;br /&gt;
100g butter (melted)&lt;br /&gt;
1tsp vanilla &lt;br /&gt;
200g pumpkin puree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a large bowl, mix together the flour, sugar, baking powder, salt, cinnamon, cloves and nutmeg.  In a separate bowl, whisk together the milk, eggs, melted butter, vanilla and pumpkin until fully combined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pour the wet ingredients into the dry ingredients and mix into a smooth, thick batter. 
Heat a non-stick pan over a medium heat with a little oil.  Add a ladle of batter and cook until bubbles start to appear on the surface.  Flip the pancake and cook for a further 2 minutes (the pancake should start to puff up a little).  Once all of the mix is used up, stack the pancakes high and enjoy.  I like to top mine with grilled bacon, chopped pecans and a drizzle of maple syrup but whipped cream and a sprinkle of cinnamon works well, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pumpkin-pie&quot;&gt;Pumpkin Pie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pumpkin_pie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my ultimate favourite autumn treat.  I always look forward to the start of the season so I can start making pumpkin pie!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;350g shortcrust pastry &lt;br /&gt;
1 egg&lt;br /&gt;
425g can pumpkin puree&lt;br /&gt;
235ml evaporated milk&lt;br /&gt;
220g caster sugar&lt;br /&gt;
¼ tsp ground cloves&lt;br /&gt;
1 tsp salt&lt;br /&gt;
1 tsp ground cinnamon&lt;br /&gt;
½ ground ginger&lt;br /&gt;
1 tbsp plain flour&lt;br /&gt;
Whipped cream to serve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat the oven to 170 
Dust a clean work surface with a little flour and roll out the pastry. Line a greased pie dish with the pastry and trim the edges with a sharp knife.&lt;br /&gt;
Put the egg, pumpkin puree, evaporated milk, sugar, cloves, salt, cinnamon, ginger and flour into a large bowl and mix until all of the ingredients are combined and the mixture is smooth.
Pour the mixture into the pie crust and bake for around 30 minutes or until the filling is firm and doesn’t wobble.  &lt;em&gt;I then switch the oven off, open the oven door a little and leave the pie in there while it starts to cool.  I find that doing this stops the filling from cracking as it cools because it is cooling more gradually than if I took it straight out of the oven.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After around 20 minutes, take the pie out of the oven and leave to cool completely.  Serve with a good dollop of whipped cream and a sprinkle of cinnamon and nutmeg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pumpkin-loaf&quot;&gt;Pumpkin Loaf&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pumpkin_loaf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works for breakfast, brunch or just as a snack.  I love it griddled and buttered so that it goes crispy on the outside and squidgy on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;300g plain flour&lt;br /&gt;
½ tsp salt&lt;br /&gt;
1 tsp baking soda&lt;br /&gt;
½ tsp baking powder&lt;br /&gt;
1 tsp ground cloves &lt;br /&gt;
1 tsp ground cinnamon &lt;br /&gt;
1 tsp ground nutmeg &lt;br /&gt;
170g unsalted butter (at room temperature)&lt;br /&gt;
400g caster sugar&lt;br /&gt;
2 large eggs&lt;br /&gt;
1 425g can pumpkin puree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat the oven to 160º. Grease a loaf tin with butter and dust with flour.
In a medium bowl, add the flour, salt, baking soda, baking powder, cloves, cinnamon, and nutmeg and mix until well combined, set aside.
Using an electric mixer, beat the butter and sugar on medium speed until just blended. Add the eggs one at a time, beating well. Continue beating until very light and fluffy, this should take 2 or 3 minutes. Add the pumpkin and continue to beat for one minute.
Add the flour mixture and mix on low speed until combined.
Pour the batter into the loaf tin and bake for 1 hour and 15 mins or until a cake tester inserted into the centre comes out clean. Let the loaf cool in the tin for around 10 minutes before carefully turning out onto a wire rack to cool completely.
          I like to griddle slices of pumpkin loaf until they are slightly charred then eat them with butter on.  Delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pumpkin-spiced-doughnut-holes&quot;&gt;Pumpkin Spiced Doughnut Holes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/doughnut_holes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be warned, once you have one, you will want more! These are a perfect little treat for a Halloween movie night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;225g plain flour&lt;br /&gt;
2 tsp baking powder&lt;br /&gt;
½ tsp salt&lt;br /&gt;
1 tsp cinnamon&lt;br /&gt;
¼ tsp ground cloves&lt;br /&gt;
½ tsp ground nutmeg&lt;br /&gt;
¾ can pumpkin puree&lt;br /&gt;
110g brown sugar&lt;br /&gt;
80ml vegetable oil&lt;br /&gt;
1 egg&lt;br /&gt;
1 tsp vanilla extract&lt;br /&gt;
120ml milk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sugar coating&lt;br /&gt;
110g unsalted butter, melted&lt;br /&gt;
130g granulated sugar&lt;br /&gt;
1 tbsp cinnamon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this recipe, I used a silicone cake pop mould, however, if you don’t have one of these you can also use a cupcake or mini cupcake tin. 
Preheat the oven to 170ºc and, if using a cupcake tin, generously grease the tin with butter.  In a large bow, mix together the flour, baking powder, salt, ground cloves, nutmeg and cinnamon.
In a separate bowl, mix together the pumpkin puree, brown sugar, vegetable oil, vanilla extract, egg and milk until smooth.
Pour the dry ingredients into the wet ingredients and stir in until everything is combined.  Be careful not to overmix.
Scoop the better into the cupcake tin (about ¾ full) or silicon mould and bake for around 10-12 minutes.
Remove the donuts from the oven and allow to cool a little, so that they are still warm but cool enough to handle.
In the meantime, place the melted butter in one bowl and the sugar and cinnamon in another.
Dip each donut hole into the butter then coat generously with the cinnamon sugar.&lt;br /&gt;
Serve warm!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pumpkin-recipes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pumpkin-recipes/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Food</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
